Two dads, one toy, no prisoners.
Jingle All the Way is a family, comedy, adventure film directed by Brian Levant.
Howard Langston, a salesman for a mattress company, is
constantly kept busy at his job, disappointing his son.
After he misses his son's karate exposition, Howard vows to make it up to him by buying
an action figure of his son's favorite television hero for Christmas.
Unfortunately for Howard, it is Christmas Eve, and
every store is sold out of Turbo Man.
Now, Howard must travel all over town and compete with
everybody else to find a Turbo Man action figure.
Howard Langston, played by Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Myron Larabee, played by Sinbad.
Ted Maltin, played by Phil Hartman.
Liz Langston, played by Rita Wilson.
Officer Hummell, played by Robert Conrad.
D.J., played by Martin Mull.
Jingle All the Way is a 1996 American Christmas family
comedy film directed by Brian Levant.
The film stars Arnold Schwarzenegger and Sinbad as Howard Langston and Myron Larabee, two rival fathers living in Minneapolis desperately
trying to purchase the popular Turbo Man action figure for their respective sons on a last-minute shopping spree on Christmas Eve.
The film's title is borrowed from the lyrics of the
popular Christmas song "Jingle Bells".
The film was written by Randy Kornfield.
Producer Chris Columbus rewrote the script, adding in elements of satire about the
commercialization of Christmas, and the project was picked up by 20th Century Fox.
Delays to Fox's reboot of Planet of the Apes allowed Schwarzenegger to come on board the
film, while Columbus opted to cast Sinbad instead of Joe Pesci as Myron.
Jingle All the Way was set and filmed in the Twin Cities of Minneapolis and Saint
Paul at a variety of locations, including the Mall of America.
After five weeks of filming, production moved to California,
where scenes such as the end parade were shot.
The film's swift production meant merchandising was limited to a
replica of the Turbo Man action figure used in the film.
Upon release, Jingle All the Way grossed $129.8 million but received
generally negative reviews from critics for its uneven tone.
In 2001, Fox was ordered to pay $19 million to Murray Hill Publishing for stealing
the idea for the film; the verdict was overturned three years later.
Jingle All the Way is the third and final collaboration between Sinbad and Phil Hartman after Coneheads (1993) and Houseguest
(1995), and the last film featuring Hartman to be released during his lifetime before he was murdered in 1998.
In 2014, the film was followed by a sequel in name only, Jingle
All the Way 2, starring Larry the Cable Guy.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship,
holiday, minnesota, christmas party, santa claus.
The tone is lighthearted.